the-ambient.com 2019-08-28

# Privacy policy - The Ambient

Details on cookies, security, GDPR, your data and everything else privacy related while you're on The Ambient 

The Ambient is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. Although we will do our utmost to protect your information, we cannot guarantee the security of the data you submit to our website; any transmission is at your own risk.

It is important that you read this privacy notice carefully plus any other fair processing notice we might send you on specific occasions so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data

Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures to try to prevent unauthorised access. This website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to minors.

We will never pass on information about you unless we are legally obliged to do so. We will never use any of your data in ways that have unjustified adverse effects on you.

The Ambient contains links to third party stores and websites. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and are not affiliated with us. It is your responsibility to check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will do our best and take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

## Controller

Wareable LTD (trading as the-ambient.com) is the data controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as "The Ambient", "we", "us" or "our" in this privacy notice).

We have appointed a data protection manager who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy policy. If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights including deletion and right-to-be-forgotten , please contact the data protection manager using the details set out below.

 **Contact details:**

Full name of Legal Entity: James Stables  
Role: Data Protection Manager  
Email address: [privacy@the-ambient.com  
](mailto:privacy@wareable.com)Postal address:

Wareable Ltd  
Studio 103 The Pill Box  
115 Coventry Road  
London  
E2 6GG

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO), the authority for data protection issues (ico.org.uk). We would appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us first if you have any specific queries.

We will report any unlawful data breach of this website's database or the database(s) of any of our third party data processors to any and all relevant persons and authorities within 72 hours of the breach if it is apparent that personal data stored in an identifiable manner has been stolen.

This privacy policy may change periodically inline with legislation developments. We will not explicitly inform our website users of these changes. We recommend that you check this page occasionally for any updates that might affect you.

## How we protect your information

We store the personal information we collect on secure servers directly controlled by us and are fully committed to ensuring your data is secure at all times. From time to time we may use third party cloud technology partners to help us store and process some of this data. In those cases, we enter into data protection agreements with these third party providers, to ensure that they use similar levels of protection and they adhere to our privacy policy. We also make sure that your personal information is transmitted in accordance with these agreements and as securely as possible using industry standard practices.

## Data summary

How we use your data and under what basis:

Activity

| 

Type of Data

| 

Basis  
  
---|---|---  
  
When you register or make a comment on our website

| 

Contact

Profile

Technical

| 

Mutually beneficial relationship

Our legitimate interest (updating records and understanding how our users use our services)  
  
We maintain our relationship (to include feedback requests and changes to our policies)

| 

Contact

Profile

Usage

| 

Mutually beneficial relationship

Legal compliance

Our legitimate interest (updating records and understanding how our users use our services)  
  
If you agree to receiving correspondence from us (to include sending updates and news from our websites, including relevant content but also administrative updates such as site maintenance and reporting)

| 

Contact

Technical

Profile

Usage

Communications and Marketing

| 

Our legitimate interest (updating records and understanding how users use our services)

Our legitimate interests (for running our business)

Legal compliance  
  
If you join our email marketing list to participate in promotions and competitions

| 

Contact

Profile

Communications and Marketing

| 

Our legitimate interest (updating records and understanding how users use our services)  
  
When you use our site

| 

Technical

Usage

| 

Our legitimate interest (updating records and understanding how users use our services)  
  
## Where your information is stored

You data is stored in a secure cloud - cloud data can be stored within multiple locations by our cloud service providers, from time to time your information may be transferred to and stored in secure locations outside the EEA

Regular audits and appropriate safeguards are in place for all transfers both within and outside of the EEA

## How we share information

We never disclose your personal data unless it is with your consent or as authorised or required by law. We may share your personal information collected with third party service providers to help us provide our services to you, such as sending you notification emails, and only if such information is required to provide you with the specific services. When we do this, we enter into data protection agreements with these service providers and ensure that they all comply with our privacy policy. In cases when we are providing these webpages on behalf of another party, we may share personal & usage data only with the party we are providing the service for and according to its instructions.

Your rights and how you can access or modify your personal information

You can at any time request deletion of or amendments to your data by emailing us on privacy@the-ambient.com.

Upon receipt of your request, we will remove your data from our mailing list and your login to our website will be removed within 30 days. Any emails and contact form requests will be stored for 90 days before being deleted.

You have the right to:  
Request access to your data (ask us what information we store related to you)  
Request correction to your data  
Request erasure  
Request transfer of your data  
Withdraw consent at any time

Our website is fully compliant with v3.2 of the PCI DSS standards and undertakes regular testing of its systems and processes to ensure ongoing compliance.

Our website is not aimed at children and we do not knowingly collect the data of minors.

We will process your request within 15 business days.

## If you comment on our website

If you decide to register on our site and make comments on any of our articles, the username and email address you enter and your comment will be saved to our database, along with your computer's IP address and the timestamp of the comment. This profile information is only used to identify you as a contributor within the article's comment section and is not passed on to any third party data processors.

You should avoid publishing or posting any personally identifiable information. Upfeat is not responsible for content that you post on our website and we ask you do not post content that could violate the privacy of others.

Your comment and any data associated with it will remain on this site until we either remove the comment or remove the blog post. If you wish to have the comment and it's associated personal data deleted, please email us here using the email address that you commented with.

## If you email us

When you contact us through the website or fill out our online form, we collect contact data from you, such as your name and email address. This information is only used to fulfil the service you have requested or to contact you in regards to your inquiries.

## If you opt in to our newsletter

If you choose to join our email newsletter and provide your contact data to us, we'll use it to send you updates, communications and marketing from our website as well as any promotions or competitions we might run for our subscribers in future.

Your contact data will be forwarded to our email marketing provider, a compliant third party data processor. Your email address will remain within the marketing provider's database for as long as we continue to use their services for email marketing or until you specifically request removal from the list. You can do this by unsubscribing using the unsubscribe links contained in any email newsletters that we send you or by requesting removal via email at any time.

## When you use our site

When you visit our website, we use cookies to collect technical and usage data, such as your IP address or unique device id. We use this information to understand how you use our site features, and your browsing habits. This helps us to evolve our website with you in mind, ensuring we make smart decisions and you can have the best browsing experience. Cookie usage also helps us to prevent malicious behaviour and abuse of services, protecting our site and the people who use it.

We and our providers also make use of cookies to help promote our services through marketing and advertising. At no time do we pass any cookie personal data to a third party for their own purposes.

You can opt-out of cookies or prevent third party websites from accessing our cookies through the privacy settings on your browser. That will disable, however, some features of our website.

## How we protect your information

We store the personal information we collect on secure servers directly controlled by us and are fully committed to ensuring your data is secure at all times. From time to time we may use third party cloud technology partners to help us store and process some of this data. In those cases, we enter into data protection agreements with these third party providers, to ensure that they use similar levels of protection and they adhere to our privacy policy. We also make sure that your personal information is transmitted in accordance with these agreements and as securely as possible using industry standard practices.

## IP Addresses and Cookies

We may collect information about your IP address in order to maintain a safe environment for our users. We may analyse details of your visits to our site or your use of the app, including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data and other communication data and the resources that you access.

We may obtain information about your usage of the website by using a cookie file.

Websites use cookies to make the browsing experience more efficient, and to help you use websites to their full potential. Cookies are a small text file that is transferred to your hard drive or the internal memory of your mobile device.

## What do our cookies do?

They help you to personalise your experience with our site, allowing you to engage with the The Ambient fully. Our cookies enable you to comment and stay signed in while you browse the site.

They ensure your sign up process is as efficient as possible, we use cookies as a way to authenticate you as a registered user, allowing you to fully personalise your user profile and settings, including local deals location.

They allow us to track affiliate activity. Some merchants pay commission when you go to their site from The Ambient.

Our cookies do not share any of your personal data with us, and we would never use any information derived from cookies to try to identify anybody.

We use cookies to personalise content and adverts, to provide social media features and to analyse our traffic. We also share information about your use of our site with our social media, advertising and analytics partners.

Ads you see on The Ambient will have been placed by third parties. These third parties may generate their own cookies for the purposes of collecting anonymous information relating to their advertising. This information collected cannot be used to personally identify someone.

If you want to restrict or block cookies, you can do so in your browser settings.

By using The Ambient you agree to the guidelines set out in our privacy policy. If you want to find out more about cookies or if you want to know how to delete or control the cookies that are stored on your computer you can visit AboutCookies.org.

## Glossary

 **The data we collect about you**

Personal data, or personal information, is any information about an person or individual from which that person can be uniquely identified. It doesn't include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous or anonymised data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you:

• Contact Data: This includes data relating to how you may be contacted, such as your email address.

• Technical Data: This includes data that we may obtain when you make use of our website, such as your IP address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, operating system, device or platform.

• Profile Data: This includes the data that we receive when you create a profile on our website, such as your login info, username and password

• Usage Data: This includes information about how you use our website

• Marketing and Communications Data: This includes your preferences in relation to whether or not you want to receive newsletters and updates from us and your communication preferences / settings"

How we collect your personal data

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

## Direct interactions

You may give us your Profile and Contact data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes the data you provide when you:

• Create a username on our website;

• Subscribe to our newsletter, updates or other publications;

• Request marketing and news to be sent to you;

• Enter a competition, promotion or survey;

• Give us some feedback on our site or our app.

## Contact details

Full name of Legal Entity: James Stables  
Role: Data Protection Manager  
Email address: [privacy@the-ambient.com  
](mailto:privacy@wareable.com)Postal address:

Wareable Ltd  
Studio 103 The Pill Box  
115 Coventry Road  
London  
E2 6GG
